John W. Tukey Papers 1937-2000 Mss.Ms.Coll.117
American Philosophical Society
- Series VI. Organizations, 1947-1995; 18 linear feet
  President’s Science Advisory Committee, 1957-1992
  (Rand) Research and Development, 1945-1992
  Society for Industry and Applied Mathematics (SIAM), 1954-1993
  Xerox PARC, 1972-1992
- Series VII. Personal, 1937-1999; 4 linear feet
  Consists of personal correspondence and family photos, boxes of index cards, appointment books, and awards, medals, I.D. cards and dozens of tiny address books. Also included: doctoral research (1937), a 1957 diary, and “message books,” (1980-1992). Also in the series is material on folk dancing, post cards, news clippings and assorted family photos of Tukey's wife, Elizabeth, and his parents, Ralph and Ada Tukey.
- Series VIII. Printed Materials, 1942-1991; 4 linear feet
  Consists mostly of industrial and military books, pamphlets, and reports, reprints and publications from the American Statistical Association, National Science Foundation, and National Academy of Sciences. Also included are books and pamphlets on folk dancing.
- Series IX. Graphics, 1930's-1990's; 6 linear feet
  The Graphics series, arranged alphabetically, is a mixture of computer discs, audio and visual tapes, and photographs.
  Included in the series is one linear feet of stray floppy discs (1987-1990) and 21 data cartridge tapes, (1988-1989); and a box of 11 discs labeled, PIMI PIMA.Doc (6/2/1994). Other items include 4 large tapes containing “Uncropped Bell Labs Frequency data" (7 Jan. 1971) and 3 tapes labeled, “Att. Management Survey (n.d.).” Also included is a series of Tukey portraits taken over the years, an IBM workshop shot (1948); photos of the Geneva Arms Control Talks, (1959); casual photos taken at the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, (1957-1958); photos taken during NBC’s Operation Ballot, (1968); group photos of the President’s Science Advisory Committee, (1959-[1963]).
  Photos of Tukey’s Princeton colleagues, the Mathematics Department Princeton, and some photos of Tukey lecturing are included among the professional graphics. The Bell Laboratory photos contain group shots of Tukey and colleagues. Also included is a collection of VHS video tapes of consensus material and an interview with John Tukey. Most of Tukey's personal snapshots of Princeton and elsewhere have been digitized.
  Among the video tapes is a John Tukey Educational Testing Services seminar, (1990-1996). There are a number of thumbnail photos of Tukey’s early days at Princeton University featuring photos of Tukey’s Princeton friends and colleagues, classroom scenes, and social gatherings; a 14-tape (Beta format) collection of the first American Statistical Association First Annual Statistical Short Course (1975); and 7 tapes containing Citation Index material (n.d.).
  One linear feet of cassette tapes contains lectures such as “The Analysis of Data—Exploration as one Road to Discovery” (May 15, 1975; UC Berkeley); “An Unexplored Opportunity,” Prof. John W. Tukey, meeting of the Classification Society of North America, St. John’s Newfoundland, 13 July 1985; and 14 cassettes of Princeton Robustness Week (1981).
  The personal material contains 6 boxes of personal slides, mostly travel and vacation shots, reel-to-reel tapes and photos of friends and colleagues. The photos (19927-1990) include a birding expedition, camping trips and travel, weddings, and other family gatherings.
- Series X. Research, 1944-1988; 6 linear feet
  The Research series is arranged alphabetically according to project/paper title. Occasionally the folder title is a rough draft of a paper found in Series II, Works by Tukey. Much of the material in the series is undated. The earliest material appears to be a folder of “Blotto Problem” material, (1948). There is much material on analysis of variance (ANOVA) as well as folders of material Tukey called “Badman,” and “Nachless,” both largely undated. Also included is miscellaneous correspondence, material concerning cancer rates, Exploratory Data Analysis, and material relating to graphs and graphing. There is much exploratory data analysis material and many folders of miscellaneous research material, 1940-1965 and undated research. Included in the series is Nike missile data (1946, 1952); noise data (1984); Phipps-Cochrane material (1947-1948); “Re-expression” material; undated material on “time series;” tuberculosis data; and weather-rainfall data.
- Series XI. Subject Files, 1946-1997; 5 linear feet
  The Subject Files is arranged alphabetically according to subject.
  Arms Control, 1949-1995
  Census, 1963-1992
  Elections, 1948-1980
  Environment, 1945-1993
  Early computers, 1936-1957
  Flexagons, 1949-1977
  Kinsey materials, 1929-1952
  National Defense, 1957-1967
  Race-Bias Case, 1996-1997
  Security Clearances, 1950-1990
  Wilks, Samuel, 1964